<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Undervalued</title>
    <link>http://undervaluedblog.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Undervalued</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 13:52:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://undervaluedblog.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Market Returns Based on Presidential Party</title>
      <link>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/02/stock-market-returns-based-on-presidential-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 13:52:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/02/stock-market-returns-based-on-presidential-party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the election, a few people have made comments along the lines of &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Trump will be good for stocks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. The implication is that Republican presidents are better for the stock market since they are generally viewed as being pro-business. It amazes me that this assumption is pervasive given stock market performance for the last three presidents. However, since I recently read &lt;a href=&#34;http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/02/the-undoing-project&#34;&gt;The Undoing Project&lt;/a&gt;, I was cognizant of any biases I may have and decided to look at the avialable data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before presenting the data, I should confess that I view this analysis as futile. I do not believe that one should make investing decisions solely based on the president (and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/02/13/upshot/its-probably-a-bad-idea-to-sell-stocks-because-you-fear-trump.html&#34;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt; agree). Nor do I believe that the president (or Congress) has much influence over the stock market&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fed&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:fed&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Many factors are out of the president&amp;rsquo;s control. For example, President George W. Bush inherited a stock market bubble and left office in a deep bear market and recession&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:bush&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:bush&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For stock market returns, I used the adjusted close of the S&amp;amp;P500. &lt;a href=&#34;http://finance.yahoo.com/quote/%5EGSPC?p=^GSPC&#34;&gt;Yahoo&lt;/a&gt; provides data through the Truman administration. The list of presidents and corresponding inauguration dates is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Presidents_of_the_United_States&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. The data and analysis are available as a Jupyter notebook&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:jupyter&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:jupyter&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/crewsj/data_analysis/blob/master/examples/stock_returns/presidential_returns.ipynb&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:mistakes&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:mistakes&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, the total and annualized return when each party controlled the presidency:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Presidential Party&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Total Return (%)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Annual Return (%)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Republican&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;354.79&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;4.30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Democrat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2896.92&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;10.01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you invested only when the Democrats controlled the executive branch, you would have a nearly 30x return on your money. If you invested only when the Republicans controlled the executive branch, you would have approximately a 4.5x return on your money. Democrats turned $1 into $30; Republicans turned $1 into $4.5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference shocked me but if we look at the returns for each president we can see why. The results per president in chronological order are below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://undervaluedblog.com/images/total_return_chrono.png&#34; alt=&#34;total return&#34; title=&#34;total return&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://undervaluedblog.com/images/annual_return_chrono.png&#34; alt=&#34;annual return&#34; title=&#34;annual return&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ranking the results show just how much Clinton and Obama dominated&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dominated&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:dominated&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. All the other Democratic presidents would have given you approximately at 3x return on your money, while Obama and Clinton added nearly another 10x on top of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://undervaluedblog.com/images/annual_return_ranked.png&#34; alt=&#34;annual return ranked&#34; title=&#34;annual return ranked&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losing 40% during President George W. Bush&amp;rsquo;s adminstration compared to 182% and 209% returns for Obama and Clinton, respectively, really hurt the Republicans&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:rule&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:rule&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. If we take out the last three presidents&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:stupid&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:stupid&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, the results are more even with a 6.48% annualized return for the Democrats and a 7.51% annualized return for the Republicans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other interesting thing that stood out to me was George H. W. Bush&amp;rsquo;s&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:hwbush&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:hwbush&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; position in the rankings. He is the second best Republican and hardly deserves being remembered for losing to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It%27s_the_economy,_stupid&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the economy, stupid&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I will look at other statistics such as unemployment rate, manufacturing indices, etc. I would also like to include the party controlling congress in the results. More to come&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fed&#34;&gt;The Federal Reserve is a different matter&amp;hellip;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fed&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:bush&#34;&gt;I do not blame President Bush (or Republicans) for the Great Recession, financial crisis, whatever you want to call it. Many people would disagree with me, but Glass-Steagall was &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gramm%E2%80%93Leach%E2%80%93Bliley_Act&#34;&gt;repealed&lt;/a&gt; on Clinton&amp;rsquo;s watch. I don&amp;rsquo;t blame President Clinton either.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:bush&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:jupyter&#34;&gt;Not sure how I feel about &lt;a href=&#34;http://jupyter.org/&#34;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll have more on that later. For simple analyses that you want to share, it works pretty well though.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:jupyter&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:mistakes&#34;&gt;Email mistakes to undervaluedblog [at] gmail.com
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:mistakes&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dominated&#34;&gt;Not sure if &amp;ldquo;dominated&amp;rdquo; is the right word.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dominated&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:rule&#34;&gt;Buffett&amp;rsquo;s rule number 1: &amp;ldquo;Never lose money.&amp;rdquo; Rule number 2: &amp;ldquo;See rule number 1.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:rule&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:stupid&#34;&gt;And without Lebron the Cavs wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have won. I realize this makes a futile analysis even dumber.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:stupid&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:hwbush&#34;&gt;Big fan.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:hwbush&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading What Everyone Else is Reading</title>
      <link>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/02/reading-what-everyone-else-is-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 13:32:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/02/reading-what-everyone-else-is-reading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-mission/wtf-i-just-spent-1-207-40-on-books-6e5639e1f7bc#.1x9e30917&#34;&gt;Shane Parrish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:parrish&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:parrish&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading is not only the key to improving your lot in life, but it’s necessary if you want to develop insights, ideas, and understanding that sets you apart from others. You can’t however, &lt;strong&gt;read what everyone else is reading&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only minor quibble here is that it should be stated: you can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; read what everyone else is reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am an engineer. I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; art. However, I distinctly remember standing in a museum in Spain with fellow study abroad students. I was shocked at how &lt;em&gt;normal&lt;/em&gt; Picasso&amp;rsquo;s earlier works were&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:Picasso&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:Picasso&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Picasso to me was synonymous with cubism. A fellow student (Park Scholar, very bright) explained to me that you have to understand the rules before you can break them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My point is that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t avoid reading what others are reading, and I doubt that is Shane&amp;rsquo;s suggestion. There is even value in understanding what everyone is reading, and things become popular for a reason. Not everyone will be or wants to be the next Elon Musk or Richard Thaler, someone who has mastered Howard Mark&amp;rsquo;s second-level thinking&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:marks&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:marks&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. To master second-level thinking (if that is even possible) requires understanding the rules first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:parrish&#34;&gt;I would highly recommend subscribing to his weekly newsletter, available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/&#34;&gt;Farnam Street blog&lt;/a&gt;. Shane Parrish and &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net&#34;&gt;John Gruber&lt;/a&gt; are the two main reasons I decided to start a blog. Oh and &lt;a href=&#34;http://superfluoussextant.com/&#34;&gt;Superfluous Sextant&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:parrish&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:Picasso&#34;&gt;And everyone is probably shocked at my lack of culture. I am an engineer! If I were trying to impress people in the wine and cheese crowd, I would talk about how these pieces were likely from his Blue Period or Rose Period. But I hang out with Bud Light&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:sponsor&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:sponsor&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; crowds, and these paintings seemed &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;normal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to me.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:Picasso&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:marks&#34;&gt;More on this later but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oaktreecapital.com/docs/default-source/memos/2015-09-09-its-not-easy.pdf?sfvrsn=2&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is one reference: &amp;ldquo;Different and better: that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good description of second-level thinking.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:marks&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:sponsor&#34;&gt;AB Inbev&amp;hellip; sponsor? Call me.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:sponsor&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Undoing Project</title>
      <link>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/02/the-undoing-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 21:35:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/02/the-undoing-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Lewis is one of my favorite authors, and I typically look forward to his latest book. However, I was especially looking forward to &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2kdfVMN&#34;&gt;The Undoing Project&lt;/a&gt; since it is a book about Daniel Kahneman and Amos Tversky. I became interested in behavioral economics&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:investing&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:investing&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, a field Kahneman and Tversky revolutionized, after reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2l4O6YC&#34;&gt;Misbehaving&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2l9AqaY&#34;&gt;The Little Book of Behavioral Investing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Undoing Project starts where &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2jP3Ytr&#34;&gt;Moneyball&lt;/a&gt; left off, except this time with the story of the Houston Rockets General Manager Daryl Morey. After the first chapter, I was telling people The Undoing Project would be Lewis&amp;rsquo; best book yet. However, after finishing the book, I have a hard time recommending it to anyone who has read &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2l9nTnP&#34;&gt;Thinking Fast and Slow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:tfs&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:tfs&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The most interesting parts were the stories about Israel and how the conflicts (Six-Day War, Yom Kippur War, and others) affected Israeli citizens. Those stories made me want to read more about the history of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After listening to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/nate-silver-interviews-michael-lewis-about-his-new-book-the-undoing-project/&#34;&gt;538 podcast with Michael Lewis&lt;/a&gt; my expectations were fairly high about the personal story in this book: the depth of the friendship between Kahneman and Tversky. I was surprised at the level of candor between the two friends, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think the book exactly matched my expectations. If you are a fan of Michael Lewis or if you are unfamiliar with the work by Kahneman and Tversky, I would still recommend reading this book. It is, after all, a work by Michael Lewis, the greatest nonfiction writer of our time. It may not rank with his best (&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2jP3Ytr&#34;&gt;Moneyball&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2l4V0Nu&#34;&gt;Liar&amp;rsquo;s Poker&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2jM6BB3&#34;&gt;The Big Short&lt;/a&gt;) but it is still an enjoyable read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:investing&#34;&gt;I used to think that personal investors could simply outperform the market by buying cheap (as measured by price/cash flow) and efficient (as measured by return on invested capital) companies. However, these days I believe buying undervalued stocks is a necessary condition, it is not a sufficient condition. Pyschological advantages are the sufficient conditions. I have read many books on Warren Buffett and his letters to shareholders. I have never seen him write about hard and fast valuation metrics. I will need to dig up the quote by &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2k7UE4y&#34;&gt;Alice Schroeder&lt;/a&gt; but I think she claimed that he had written at least some metrics down for her but she couldn&amp;rsquo;t publish them until his death (&lt;em&gt;As I write that, it sounds like an alternative fact, so I could be imagining things&lt;/em&gt;). However, Buffett has written extensively about his pyschological advantages, and I believe that is the real source of his outperformance.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:investing&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:tfs&#34;&gt;Full disclaimer here: I read parts of Thinking Fast and Slow but not cover to cover, which I hope to do soon.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:tfs&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malcolm Gladwell on Freakonomics Radio</title>
      <link>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/02/malcolm-gladwell-on-freakonomics-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 12:20:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/02/malcolm-gladwell-on-freakonomics-radio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are missing your fix of Malcolm Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s voice&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:gladwell&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:gladwell&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I would highly recommend this older episode of &lt;a href=&#34;http://freakonomics.com/podcast/malcolm-gladwell/&#34;&gt;Freakonomics Radio&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principles of deliberate practice strike me as being most useful on questions like, “How to think?” So the whole notion that you would — when you have made a decision, when you have considered a set of data or evidence and drawn some conclusion — that you would submit your process to some kind of either internal or external review. I’m trying to figure out how to do a better job the next time. That strikes me as what we need. Because, you know, one of his observations about deliberate practice is that &lt;strong&gt;practice becomes useless when it’s unreflective&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gladwell discusses the misinterpretation of his interpretation of Anders Ericsson&amp;rsquo;s work in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Outliers-Story-Success-Malcolm-Gladwell/dp/0316017930/&#34;&gt;Outliers&lt;/a&gt;. Many people focus on the 10,000 hour rule and believe Gladwell misinterpreted Ericsson&amp;rsquo;s work. However, Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s intent with Outliers was broader:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But one is that I wanted people to move away from the notion of success as something individual. And I wanted to get people to understand that a lot of success has to do with chance, with the contribution of your culture, your generation, your family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:gladwell&#34;&gt;I would also highly recommend Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s podcast &lt;a href=&#34;http://revisionisthistory.com/about/&#34;&gt;Revisionist History&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the episodes &lt;em&gt;Carlos Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Remember&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Food Fight&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;My Little Hundred Million&lt;/em&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:gladwell&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Blog</title>
      <link>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/01/about-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 21:37:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://undervaluedblog.com/2017/01/about-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I finally set up my blog after thinking about it for a while. It was easy and cheap thanks to the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;http://superfluoussextant.com/how-to-make-blog.html&#34;&gt;Superfluous Sextant&lt;/a&gt;. On the technical side, I decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; instead of a Python static site generator&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:hugo&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:hugo&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, even though I am a big fan of Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started this blog in order to write about programming, data analysis, finance&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:finance&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:finance&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, sports, interesting articles, books I am reading, and whatever else comes to mind.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:politics&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:politics&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The name of the blog (undervalued) comes from my love of researching stocks and hopefully finding undervalued companies. I am a hobbyist deep value investor and contrarian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the models for this blog is &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net&#34;&gt;Daring Fireball&lt;/a&gt;. I like how Gruber links to stories, offers plenty of snark, and also writes longer opinion pieces.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:sears&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:sears&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:hugo&#34;&gt;The suggestion for using Hugo also came &lt;a href=&#34;http://superfluoussextant.com/&#34;&gt;Superfluous Sextant&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:hugo&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:finance&#34;&gt;Usual disclaimer here&amp;hellip; I am not a financial expert or licensed in any way to give financial advice. The opinions expressed here are solely my own and should not be taken as financial advice. Consult a professional (ideally one with fiduciary duty to you) before making financial decisions.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:finance&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:politics&#34;&gt;I am still undecided about political writing on here. Although &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/im-loyal-to-nothing-except-the-dream/&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://avc.com/2017/01/make-america-hate-again/&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; technical people are writing about political issues. I would highly recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/im-loyal-to-nothing-except-the-dream/&#34;&gt;Jeff Atwood&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt; since it kind of mirrors my thinking.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:politics&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:sears&#34;&gt;I have always wanted to point out how ridiculous it is that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2014-09-15/sears-borrows-400-million-from-lampert-s-esl-investments&#34;&gt;accepting a loan&lt;/a&gt; from your CEO is a sign of trouble when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2014-03-24/lampert-stops-buying-sears-ious-as-cash-burns-corporate-finance&#34;&gt;not accepting a loan&lt;/a&gt; was also a sign of trouble 6 months earlier. Sears has plenty of problems, but my point is that the financial press (even publications I respect like Bloomberg) often look for correlations where there are none.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:sears&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://undervaluedblog.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 12:19:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://undervaluedblog.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A blog about programming and finance, but not financial programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disclaimer</title>
      <link>http://undervaluedblog.com/disclaimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 12:19:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://undervaluedblog.com/disclaimer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not a financial expert or licensed in any way to give financial advice. The opinions expressed here are solely my own and should not be taken as financial advice. Consult a professional (ideally one with fiduciary duty to you) before making financial decisisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please send any corrections or errors to undervaluedblog [at] gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>